(815) 274-7015 kjm1550@gmail.com kylejmonk.com

Summary

I had two classes where I learned the basics of web development. Since those classes I have been learning web development on my own using Free Code Camp and Code Academy online as well as practicing creating my own sites, including my portfolio site (kylejmonk.com) I am interested in learning more and creating a career in web development.

Languages and Skills

HTML, CSS, Java (1 year); MySQL (2 years); JavaScript, Responsive Design, Bootstrap, Search Engine Optimization, WordPress, GitHub (less than1 year).

Work Experience

Administrative Technologies Student Worker Illinois State University

November 2017 – Present Normal, Illinois

- Work with a team of six to complete and research tasks detailed by a ticketing database
- Use PowerShell commands to administrate the University's Office 365 infrastructure
- Create and manage users, distributions list, teams, shared resource calendars and video channels
- Provision and decommission physical and virtual VMware servers and manage them using Lansweeper and vSphere
- Thoroughly document, using OneNote, how to perform all tasks
- Provide excellent customer service though the ticketing software

Student Information Technology Intern Morris Hospital and Healthcare Center

May 2017 – January 2018 Morris, Illinois

- Installed, troubleshot, and configured workstations for hospital employees
- Created, tested, and deployed images for workstations using Windows Server
- Assisted the help desk team by attending to calls and tasks to troubleshoot and fix any IT issues
- Job shadowed IT department professionals including the network specialist, senior and junior systems specialists, and the help desk team
- Learned about the computing infrastructure and large self-sufficient multimillion dollar server room
- Gained experience with System Center Configuration, Track-It, Jabber, Group Policy, and VMware

Warehouse Worker

May 2015 - August 2017

Costco Distribution Center

Morris, Illinois

- Operated an electric pallet jack to transport merchandise across the warehouse
- Wrapped pallets of merchandise with a team to ensure safe transportation

Education

Bachelor of Science Degree in Computer Systems Technology Illinois State University

May 2018 GPA 3.1

Relevant Courses

TEC 319 – Created static web pages with HTML and CSS. Practiced box method, responsive design, basic SEO, and Integrated MySQL to display data. PHP was used for creating, reading, updating, and deleting data from the MySQL database using the web page as the interface.

TEC 152 – Web development was the second half of the class. Created basic sites with just HTML and CSS. Used WordPress, Adobe Dreamweaver, and Illustrator.

TEC 283 – Used Java to create programs that would creating, reading, updating, and deleting data from the MySQL database.